Guide to the Emerson Hinchliff papers, 1910-1968.
Hinchliff, Emerson papers, 1910-1968.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Emerson Hinchliff papers, 1910-1968.
41-7-1228
Emerson Hinchliff, 1892-1968.
1 cubic ft.
Newspaper clippings, a diary, photographs, correspondence, certificates, and other items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes Cornell University and Cornell Class of 1914 items; newspaper clippings by and about Hinchliff; war diary, 1918; photographs; correspondence; certificates; and other papers of Emerson Hinchliff.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Assistant alumni secretary and assistant professor of Spanish, Cornell University.
Cornell University Class of 1914.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes Cornell University and Cornell Class of 1914 items; newspaper clippings by and about Hinchliff; war diary, 1918; photographs; correspondence; certificates; and other papers of Emerson Hinchliff.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hinchliff, Emerson, 1892-1968.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Class of 1914.
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Class of 1914 miscellany, 1914-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell miscellany, 1880, 1913, 1940-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newsclippings by and about Hinchcliff, 1930-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Articles by Hinchcliff, 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Articles, etc. by or about E.H., 1942-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Articles, etc. by or about E.H., 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Statler Club Newsletter, 1951-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Emerson Hinchcliff war diary, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photographs, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Rotary News, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Inter-Class-Alumni Club, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Intelligence columns, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Letter and newsclipping from Harriet E. Hinchcliff re: Emerson Hinchcliff marriage (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Letter re: "Letter from Cornell", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Letters re: "Letter from Cornell", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
- Letters re: "Letter from Cornell", 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters re: "Letter from Cornell", 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Some letters of condolence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- 1914 class letters, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cornell Alumni News by E.H., 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Certificates: Quill and Dagger; Book and Bowl (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook, 1910-1914 (Box 2)
- Emerson Family genealogy book (Box 3)
  Contains laid in manuscripts, correspondence, etc..
- Cornell University diploma, 1914 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Cornell Alumni Association resolution written by John T. "Terry" McGovern, 1957 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Certificate: National Society of Sons of American Revolution, 1947 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Certificate: National Society of Daughters of American Revolution, n.d. (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Certificate: Université de Grenoble, Aug. 25, 1928 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Silver pitcher presented to Hinchcliff by the Class of 1914 in appreciation for forty years of devoted service; Reed and Barton sterling, 8 1/2" high, 1954; Locked closet